Sarah M. Jenkins

Denver, CO | (734) 358-4832 | sarahmjenkins88@gmail.com

SUMMARY

After 12 years working in public education, I have honed my strengths in processes and attention to detail and developed expertise in managing projects, collaborating to achieve results, leading groups with varying skills and interests, and thinking critically and creatively to solve problems that impede success. I am eager for the opportunity to go through a career change to explore new and powerful ways to make a social impact through technology. I am motivated to home my web development skills in a deeply collaborative environment.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

KNOWLEDGEWORKS (2014 – Present)

Remote

Senior Director, Policy and Advocacy Operations

2021 - Present

Serve as Chief of Staff to the Vice President of Policy and Advocacy to execute all operational and planning functions for the department and to collaborate across the organization to maximize alignment and clear communication.

- Monitor team workflows to ensure success in daily work and progress toward quarterly benchmarks.
- Lead team training and adoption of all technology and operational tools.
- Foster meaningful relationships and positive workplace culture to build team commitment to and ownership of their work.
- Lead annual planning and budgeting process by managing project calendars, collaborating with other teams, tracking capacity throughout the year, conducting collaborative goal setting, and providing individual support for team members.
- Manage team budget by collaborating with the CFO to ensure accuracy around revenue and expenses, creating new budgets for all grant and fee-for-service work, and tracking progress toward annual revenue goals.
- Design and maintain tools to demonstrate teams' progress toward goals and external impact.

Director, Policy Research and Strategic Initiatives

2018 - 2021

Led all policy research and significant grant-funded and fee-for-service projects.

- Led project to design the foundational report for all of the organization's state policy work.
 - Led project to conduct in-depth policy audits and stakeholder engagements in four states, contributing to the organization winning nine million dollars in contract work.
 - Coordinated internally and externally to increase impact of team's work by writing briefs, supervising group processes, delivering recommendations on specific policy issues, and adapting tools for external partners.
 - Designed structures to ensure team's compliance with organizational expectations through annual planning, participating in cross-functional teams, training in new technology tools, and creating annual reports for the board and tax reports.
 - Revitalized culture during the COVID-19 pandemic by leading opportunities for team building and connection.
 - Spearheaded processes to design two new tools to track progress toward organizational goals and collaborated across the
 organization to ensure compliance and appropriate use.

Senior Manager, Research and Advocacy

2016 - 2018

Created project plans, researched and wrote critical policy projects, and proved self as an organizatioal collaborator and leader.

- Fielded requests from states for guidance on policies and programs to support student-centered learning.
- Headed a research and writing process with internal and external partners to produce a paper on teachers' experiences implementing personalized learning.
- Partnered to analyze all state ESSA plans for policies and programs that support student-centered learning.
- Led the research and writing of an organization memo to reconsider our policy work to intentionally pursue equity.
- Orchestrated a six-state policy scan with internal and external partners to support a key funder's strategic planning.
- Coordinated internal research to produce guidance to become thriving organization with a high percentage of remote staff.

Policy and Research Analyst

2014 - 2016

Demonstrated rapidly gained expertise in personalized learning policy and prioritized cross-organizational relationship building.

- Co-authored two papers that became the foundation of the organization's mission and strategic direction.
- Partnered with VP of Talent and Chief of Staff to research best practices and create an organization mentoring program.
- Managed policy research and special projects across school district, state, and federal education policy.
- Designed and led a state policy scan process to create policy agendas for our state policy work.
- Co-chaired annual United Way giving campaign, raising \$50,000 with 80% employee participation.

Jenkins, cont.

THE DONNELL-KAY FOUNDATION

Fellow

Denver, CO 2013 – 2014

- Co-facilitated Colorado's 2014 K-12 Online Education Task Force by conducting research, managing public input, and assisting in the writing of the final recommendations.
- Analyzed and synthesized state education policies to inform working groups and advocacy campaigns.

COLORADO CHILDREN'S CAMPAIGN

Denver, CO

Leadership for Educational Equity (LEE) Policy Fellow

2013

Researched and presented on education finance issues to inform the strategic direction of the organization.

DENVER PUBLIC SCHOOLS (2010-2013)

Denver, CO 2010 – 2013

Classroom Teacher

• Led my classroom to achieve significant gains including closing a 10% assessment score gap between math classes, leading students to an average of 1 year of reading growth in five months, and increasing spelling test mastery from 50% to

- 90%.

 Selected as a 2010 Teach for America corps member, a competitive alternative certification program with a 13%
- acceptance rate.
 Analyzed student data and researched best practices in order to implement interventions to improve classroom culture and academic outcomes, including developing a first-grade math curriculum.
- Created a classroom culture combining high expectations for academic rigor with a joyful and safe learning environment.

EDUCATION

University of Colorado-Denver, School of Public Affairs, Master of Public Administration, 3.9 GPA
University of Michigan, Bachelor of Arts with Distinction, Dual major in French Arabic Studies, 3.8 GPA
Institut d'Etudes Françaises pour Etudiants Etrangers, Study Abroad
Aix-en-Provence, Françaises

SKILLS

Proficient: Google Suite, Salesforce, Smartsheet, Microsoft Office, SPSS, STATA, quantitative data analysis Beginner: HTML, CSS, JavaScript (classes through Codecademy and freeCodeCamp)

Other skills: Project management, writing and copy-editing, written and oral communication, human-centered management, qualitative data analysis, budgeting, contract management, strategic planning, proficient in spoken and written French

COMMUNITY INVOLVEMENT

Denver Dumb Friends League , Surgery Recovery Aide volunteer at animal shelter	2022
Soul2Soul Sisters, Participant in a program on ending anti-Black racism and white supremacy culture	2020
Girls on the Run Cincinnati, Volunteer with school-based program and at spring 5k event	2016
Young Education Professionals Cincinnati, Founder of chapter and board member	2015 - 2016
Cincinnati Public Schools, Tutor in reading and math in Title I schools	2014 - 2016
Denver Rescue Mission, Leader of a weekly children's group in afterschool activities and meal server	2013 - 2014
Teach For America—Colorado, Alumni Advisory Board member, Onboarding Coordinator, and phone screener	2011-2014